[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：好的，让我们讨论一下回调之上的模式。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: All right, let's talk about a pattern on top of callbacks.
这实际上已经存在了很长一段时间了。
This has actually been around for a really, really long time.
它的方式早于JavaScript，这个术语甚至在
It way predates JavaScript, this terminology didn't even really exist in
JavaScript，直到人们开始尝试在JavaScript中采用这个概念，并且
JavaScript until people started trying to adopt this notion in JavaScript, and
单词是Thunk
the word is Thunk.
我不知道他们是从哪里想出这个词的，
I have no idea where they came up with this word,
我不知道他们在抽什么，我希望我有一些。
I don't know what they were smoking, I wish I had some of it.
这是一个奇怪的词，我甚至不知道它的起源是什么，但我可以向你描述
It's a weird word, I don't even know what its origin is, but I can describe to you
我认为这是什么，它实际上是一种欺骗性的简单。
what I think it is and it's actually kind of deceptively simple.
从同步的角度看，Thunk是什么，Thunk是一个函数
What a Thunk is from a synchronous perspective, a Thunk is a function
这已经有了它需要做的一切，才能给你一些价值。
that has everything already that it needs to do to give you some value back.
不需要传递任何参数，只需调用它并
You do not need to pass any arguments in, you simply call it and
它会给你一个价值。
it will give you a value back.
听起来耳熟吗？
Does that sound familiar?
你还记得我们之前在不同的车间里是怎么谈论这个的吗？
You remember how we were talking about that before in a different workshop?
Thunk只是一个具有跟踪某个值的某种闭包状态的函数，
A Thunk is just a function with some closure state keeping track of some value,
或值，每当你调用函数时，它都会返回这些东西。
or values, and it gives you those things back whenever you call the function.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：这是一个同步的重击。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Here's a synchronous thunk.
我有一个add函数，它需要一个x和一个y，以及
I've got an add function, which expects an x and a y, and
我做了一个thunk，调用add函数，其中已经有了10和15。
I make a thunk that calls the add function and already has the 10 and the 15 in it.
在这种情况下是硬编码的。
It's hard coded in this case.
每次我像在线一样调用，所以这是调用add函数的第9行，
Every time I call like I do online, so that's line 9 to call the add function,
但每次我拨打9号线，如果我一遍又一遍地调用func
but every time I call line 9, if I call func over and over and
再一次，我每次都会得到相同的值。
over again, I'm gonna get the same value out every single time.
所以，现在这是最重要的部分。
So, now here's the important part.
func本身的值，它是一个函数，
Func itself value, which is a function,
它已经成为围绕特定状态集合的容器。
it has become a container around that particular collection of state.
现在这是一个容器，我可以在我的程序中的任何地方传递它，
And that is now a container that I can pass around anywhere in my program,
作为包装在那个状态周围的容器。
as a container wrapped around that state.
任何时候我想提取它，我只需调用该函数并
And any time I want to extract it, I simply have to call that function and
我把价值拿出来。
I get the value out.
我不必传递值或状态本身。
I don't have to pass the value or the state itself.
我在我的程序中传递了围绕该状态的包装器。
I passed the wrapper around that state all around my program.
所以它就像一个代表这个值的令牌，很容易把它取出来。
So it becomes like a token that represents this value and it's easy to get it out.
我所要做的就是执行它来获取值。
All I have to do is execute it to get the value out.
&GT；&GT；Kyle Simpson：你可能还没有意识到这一点，但这是根本
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: You may not realize it yet, but that is the fundamental
承诺是什么的概念基础，在这里是一个价值的包装
conceptual underpinning for what a promise is, a wrapper around a value Here
是作为承诺中的函数的包装器，它是一个更复杂的东西。
are the wrapper as a function in promises it's a much more sophisticated thing.
实际上是相当强大的思考
Was actually quite powerful to think about
当我们将电话从同步性质扩展到异步性质时。
when we extend phones from the synchronous nature into an asynchronous nature.
这是一个同步的Thunk，这是最常见的定义
This is a synchronous thunk and that's the most common definition for
他们要找到的是它是一个同步的东西。
them to find is that it's a synchronous thing.
什么是异步thunk？
What is an asynchronous thunk?
这里没有对错的定义。
Well, there's no right or wrong definition here.
但是我们可以定义异步thunk的最自然的方式是它是
But the most natural way that we could define an asynchronous thunk is that it is
一个不需要传递给它的任何参数的函数来完成它的工作，
a function that doesn't need any arguments passed to it to do its job,
除了你需要传递一个回调函数，这样你就可以得到这个值了。
except you need to pass it a callback so that you can get the value out.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：这就是我们所说的异步thunk。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: So that's what we're gonna call an asynchronous thunk.
所以让我们将同步thunk扩展到异步thunk。
So let's extend our synchronous thunk to an asynchronous thunk.
我有一个添加异步功能。
I have an add async function.
它在设定的超时时间内伪造一些异步性。
It fakes some asynchronicity with a set time out.
接受您在第1行传递的回调。
Takes the callback that you've passed in on line 1.
在第3行，它用加法调用它。
On line 3, it calls it with the addition.
所以我们在第7行用addAsync做thunk，然后我们硬编码(10，15，cb)。
So we make our thunk on line 7 with addAsync, and we hard code (10, 15, cb).
在第11行，
And on line 11,
我们有这个值，我们可以在函数中传递这个值。
we have that value that thunk value that we can pass around our function.
每次我们调用thunk并传递回调时，
And every time we call thunk and pass in a callback,
我们知道我们会得到我们的价值。
we know we're going to get our value out.
但这就是这个模式令人难以置信的强大之处。
But here's what's incredibly powerful about this pattern.
从外面的世界我们不知道也不必关心这个价值
From the outside world we do not know nor do we have to care whether that value
是立即可用还是需要一段时间才能得到那个价值。
is available immediately or whether it's gonna take a while to get us that value.
对于我们来说，我们传递一个回调有什么不同
What difference is a make to us we pass on a callback
我们知道当您为我们准备好一个值时，您将调用回调。
we know you'll call the callback when you have a value ready for us.
所以当我们第一次调用func并传入回调时，
So the first time we call func and we pass in a callback,
它可能需要做一些重要的工作来计算您的问题的答案。
it might have to do some significant work to calculate the answer to your question.
它可能会进行一些Ajax调用，并进行一些其他类型的疯狂计算，然后
It might make some ajax call, and do some other kind of crazy calculations, and
可能需要一段时间。
it might take a while.
然后它可能会决定记住这个问题的答案，所以
And then it may decide to memorize the answer to that question, so
下一次调用它时，它只会立即返回值。
the next time you call it, it just gives you the value back right away.
但是从外面的世界来看，它对我们来说是如何运作的呢？
But from the outside world does it matter to us whatsoever how that works.
这里发生的是通过将这个函数包装在状态和
What's happening here is that by wrapping this function around the state and
允许它在本质上是异步的，我们基本上已经规范化了
allowing it to be asynchronous in nature we have essentially normalized
方程中的时间，我们已经将方程中的时间考虑在内。
time out of the equation we have factored time out of the equation.
我们已经为已经成为时间无关的值制作了一个包装器。
We have produced a wrapper around the value that has become time independent.
值现在是否存在或是否存在都无关紧要
It doesn't matter if the value is there now or
如果它稍后会出现，我们仍然以完全相同的方式使用它。
if it's gonna come later we still use it in the exactly the same way.
如果你没有听到我今天说的任何其他话，请听这个。
Hear this if you don't hear anything else that I've said today.
时间是程序中最复杂的状态因素。
Time is the most complex Factor of state in your program.
管理时间是程序中最复杂的状态。
Managing time is the most complex state in your program.
这就是为什么这是巨大的，能够提出一个非常简单的，
That's why this is huge to be able to come up with a very simple,
没有涉及到库，这是直接的核心JavaScript。
there's no libraries involved, this is straight up core JavaScript.
只是从不同的角度看待和
Just a different way of looking at and
使用我们20年来一直可用的机制。
using the mechanisms that have been available to us for all 20 years.
我们采取了这个概念，这从根本上说是困难的
We've taken this notion, this fundamentally difficult
关于所谓的时间的原因，我们已经消除了它作为一个混淆的因素。
thing to reason about called time and we've eliminated it as a confusing factor.
作为一个复杂的因素。
As a complicating factor.
我有这种感觉，
I have this thunk,
它代表一个值，每当我想要这个值的时候我都会传递它，
it represents a value, I pass it around whenever I want the value,
我给它回一个电话，我把值拿出来，然后这就是我要做的所有事情。
I give it a call back and I get the value out then that's all I have to do.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：我可以从你们的表情看出你们没有意识到
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: I can tell from your faces that you're not realizing how
开创性的想法是。
groundbreaking that notion is.
好的，但这是我最重要的一个
Okay but that is one of the most important I
不敢相信，当我意识到这意味着什么时，我不能相信有多远。
couldn't believe when I recognized what that meant I could not believe how far.
我在没有意识到这一点的情况下进入了JavaScript。
I had gotten in JavaScript without that realisation.
它改变了我的一切。
It changed everything for me.
事实上，它帮助我理解了承诺。
And in fact it's what helped me understand promises.
我没有完全理解
I didn't fully understand the conceptual basis for
承诺直到我明白桑克在做什么。
promises until I understood what thunks were doing.
因为我们会发现承诺是对一个值的时间独立包装。
Because we'll find out that a promise is a time independent wrapper around a value.
只是有一个更花哨的API。
Just has a fancier API.
所以，正如我前面所说的，我喜欢说Thunks是没有花哨API的承诺。
So as I said earlier, I like to say that thunks are promises without the fancy API.
凯尔·辛普森：好吗？
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Okay?
现在有一些转折，
Now There are some twists,
在这种情况下，我们可以抛出一些皱纹。
there are some wrinkles that we can throw into the situation.
如果我想做一个Thunk，比如给自己一个通用的实用程序
If I wanted to make a Thunk like give myself a generalized utility for
做汤克。
making Thunks.
我可以做所有那些陈旧的糟糕的阵列的东西。
I can do all that old crappy array stuff and.
将参数推入并调用Apply。
Pushing the arguments on and calling apply.
我可以那样做。
I could do it that way.
我可以这样使用它，就像我们在第七行看到的那样。
And I could use it this way as we see on line seven.
所以现在我不是手动做一个，但是我可以做任何我想做的事情
So now I'm not manually making one but I can make any thunk that I
通过将回调设置为第一个参数来实现，并且
want by presetting the callback as the first argument, and
我传递的任何其他东西，都会传递给它
anything else that I pass, it's going to get passed along to it always And
这就是我能产生我的想法的方法。
that's how I could produce my thunk.
所以我可以让自己成为制造这些的公用事业，
So I could make myself a utility for making these,
从根本上讲，它与承诺构造函数没有太大的不同。
which would be not fundamentally terribly different from a promise constructor.
makeThunk有点像Promise构造函数。
makeThunk would be kinda like a promise constructor.
这是一个用于thunks的构造函数。
It's a constructor for thunks.
是啊。&gt；&gt；演讲者2：你能不能过一下，所以
Yes. &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Could you go through the, so
当我们讨论回调问题时
when we talked about the Problems of callback
这种倒置控制不能太早，不能太晚，也不能太多次。
this inversion of control not to early, not too late, not too many times.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：是的。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Yup.
&gt；&gt；演讲者2：在这一点上只是绊倒了，承诺是怎样的。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: In just to stumble bit on that with how the promise is.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：我们不会我们实际上不会有任何解决方案
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: We're not gonna we're actually not gonna have any solution to
控制的反转。
inversion of control of that.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：好的。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Yeah OK.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：承诺将解决控制反转问题。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Promises are going to solve the inversion of control.
我们还没到那一步。
We're not quite there.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：是的，好的。这让我更喜欢是的。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Yeah, okay. That makes me more Yeah.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：我们还没有解决转换控制问题。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: We haven't solved conversion control yet.
我们把概念放在
We're laying the conceptual under pinning for
承诺，这就是为什么我们要考虑这一点。
promises and that's why we're looking at that.
&gt；&gt；演讲者2：是的，我只是想引起
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Yeah, I just wanted to cause
这种认识发生在我们将要去的更早的地方。
that realization happened earlier we're going to.
现在正在更好地理解什么承诺，只是不确定
Now getting at better understanding what promises and just wasn't sure
你知道解决我们的问题的幻想有多大，或者说它有多少。
how much the fancy the is you know solving our problems or how much is it.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：是的，明白了。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Yeah, got it.
这些霹雳真的不是解决控制反转的问题
The thunks really aren't addressing inversion of control
承诺的本质是如何设计来解决这个问题的。
The nature of how promises are designed are designed to solve that.
所以我们会顺利到达的。
So we'll get there okay.
你关于再次浏览幻灯片39的问题。
Your question about going over Slide 39 again.
这是一个同步的Thunk
This is a synchronous thunk
如您所见，我有一个add函数，它接收一个X和一个Y。
as you can see I have an add function that receives an X and a Y.
我做了另一个函数thunk，它根本不需要任何参数。
And I make another function called thunk Which doesn't need any arguments at all.
thunk可以简单地调用，因为它是硬编码的
Thunk can simply be called because it is hard coded to
知道在第六行调用add函数。
know to call the add function on line six.
而且很难编码知道传入的值是10和15，也是在第6行上。
And it's hard coded to know to pass in the values 10 and 15, also on line 6.
所以无论在哪里，我们都会做一些类似于我们所做的事情
So everywhere we do something like we do on
第九行我们会得到完全相同的值。
line nine we're gonna get the exact same value.
这是一个同步的Thunk幻灯片40。
That's a synchronous thunk Slide 40.
异步版本。
The asynchronous version.
完全相同的概念，除了当我们需要传入一个回调给thunk时。
Exactly the same concept except when we need to pass in a call back to our thunk.
所以第11行，我不能只调用thunk并获得返回值。
So line 11, I can't just call thunk and get the value as a return value.
我得打电话给桑克
I have to call thunk and
给它一个回叫，它会像我在网上做的那样接收那个值。
give it a call back which will receive that value as I do on line.
你会有机会练习的，我保证。
You're going to get a chance to practice with thunks, I promise.
好吧。所以这里有一个重写
All right. So here's a rewriting of that
傻乎乎的跑步例子，用霹雳计算生命的意义。
silly running example, calculating the meaning of life By using thunks.
现在你知道一些和我以前做的略有不同的事情。
Now you know something slightly different from what I did before.
在第一行和第二行，我预先创建了一些thunks。
On lines one and two, I precreates some thunks.
我说get ten需要在调用时调用get data，值为10。
I say that get ten needs to when it's invoked call get data with the value ten.
所以第一行实际上还没有发出Ajax请求。
So line one is not actually made that Ajax request yet.
这一点很重要，你要明白。
That's important understand.
我们所做的就是创建一个包装器，当调用该包装器时，它将执行Ajax请求。
All we've done is create a wrapper that when called will do that Ajax request.
好吧。
Okay.
所以我预先设置了Get 10在Get 30 thunks中
So I pre set up the get 10 in the get 30 thunks and
我可以开始使用它们，所以在第4行我使用它。
I can start using them so on line 4 I use it.
呼叫GET 10给它回电话。
Call get 10 give it a call back.
我知道从现在开始的一千毫秒后，第一个将具有值10，然后我
I know a thousand milliseconds from now number one will have the value 10 then I
在第6行上使用get 30 thunk，这就是第9行，我创建了另一个thunk。
use the get 30 thunk on line 6 and there is the line 9 I create another thunk.
为什么我不能创造那个Thunk，第九行的那个，
Why couldn't I create that thunk, the one from line nine,
为什么我不能在第三行预先创建它？
why couldn't I pre create that up on line three?
因为它暂时依赖于前两个雷声的反应。
Because it's temporarily dependent upon the responses from the first two thunks.
大家都看到了吗。
Does everybody see that.
所以这就是为什么我不得不推迟那个特别的想法的创建。
So that's why I had to defer the creation of that particular thunk.
底线13我可以简单地呼叫得到答案，这是我的想法，我会的
Bottom line 13 I can simply call get answer which is my thunk and I will
现在得到答案的检索恰好是围绕该值的容器，并且
retrieve that now get an answer happens to be a container around that value and
我可以通过我的程序和任何需要意义的人得到答案
I can pass get an answer all over my program and anybody that needs the meaning
生活中的人可以简单的给它打个电话，然后得到答案。
of life can simply call that give it a callback and get the answer back.
这里有一些非常重要的事情需要注意，正如我所说的，重要的是要注意
There's something really important to note here as I said it's important to note that
这种特殊的表达方式，就是我想我会称之为懒惰的表达方式。
this particular expression of a thunk, is what I guess I would call a lazy thunk.
如果我真的想出一些术语
If I was really trying to come up with some terminology for
这是一个懒惰的想法，因为它不做工作。
it's a lazy thunk in that it doesn't do the work.
直到你第一次调用它。
Until you call it the first time.
你可以做一个主动的thunk，它完成了工作并保持着它的反应。
You could make an active thunk which did the work and just held on to its response.
所以它立刻做了工作，并保持了回应。
So it did the work right away and held on to the response.
这是另一种做一次重击的方式。
That is another way of doing a thunk.
我给你一个关于你即将进行的练习的巨大提示。
And I'm giving you a gigantic hint for your upcoming exercise.
&GT；&GT；演讲者3：这就像推迟一个承诺或什么。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: It's like deferring a promise or something.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：这很像是一个承诺。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: It's a lot like a promise.
这就是我想说的这些是概念上的基础。
That's what I'm saying these are the conceptual underpinnings.
所以我们现在对thunks的表达是非常懒惰的。
So our current expression of thunks is very lazy.
有可能用不同的方式来做这些事情。
It is possible to do thunks in a different way.
他们是活跃的。
Which they are active.
这意味着当他们第一次被调用时，他们第一次被设置时，他们会这样做
That means the first time they're called they do the first time they're set up they
做这项工作，他们不会给你答案，直到你通过回调。
do the work and they don't give you the answer until you pass in the callback.